PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
盒子中的皮克斯 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- The area I'm posing in is our drawing classroom.
我站着的地方是绘画教室
We call it big art because it's a really big space.
我们把它称之为大艺术 是因为它真的很大
This is where artists practice drawing models
这是艺术家练习绘制不同姿势模特的地方
The artists want to draw not only the shape
艺术家不仅要画出角色的形状
of the character, but the emotions they're expressing.
还要画出他们所表达的情感
Typically the pose is only held for a minute,
这些姿势通常来说只停留一小会儿
so you have to draw quickly and loosely.
因此你必须画得又快又松散
We call this style of drawing gestural drawing
我们把这种绘画形式称之为动态素描
and it's a great way to capture the idea
这是一种很好的方式
behind the drawing without worrying about
能够抓住画面背后的理念
capturing all the little details within the drawing.
而不用太过担心能否捕获所有的小细节
Speaking of posing, I hope you enjoyed how expressive
说到姿势 我希望你能够享受 通过几个控制器
your lamp could be with just a few controls.
就让你的台灯拥有无限的表现力
Now we're gonna add action to the emotion
现在我们将要为情感添加动作
and make your lamp jump.
让你的台灯跳起来
Think about what you do when you jump
想一想
from standing still.
你从静止到跃起是怎样的
First you bend and squash down,
首先你弯曲并下压
then you jump stretching out.
然后展开身体跃起
These are two different poses we're gonna need for our lamp,
我们得到了我们台灯所需要的两个不同的姿势
squash and stretch.
挤压和拉伸
So we need to add controls to the lamp
接下来 我们需要为台灯添加控制器
so it can move to a new location.
让它能够移动到新位置
We can do this by adding rotation and translation deformers
我们可以通过给台灯底座
to the base of the lamp.
添加旋转和移动变形器来实现它
One thing we need to be aware of when add deformers
有一项我们需要注意 当我们添加变形器的时候
is that some deformers need to operate in a certain order.
有些变形器要按一定顺序执行
This might be a little hard to picture, so let me show you.
这有点难以想象 让我告诉你
If we Rotate before we Translate, we get a different effect
在移动之前旋转
than if Translate and then Rotate.
和在旋转之前移动 会得到不同的结果
Notice that we can arrange the order of these deformers
注意 我们可以这样排列这些变形器
by clicking and dragging like this.
点击并拖拽
The order in which they operate flows in this direction.
它们按照这个方向执行
The animators who use this are moving to a position
动画师把台灯移到一个位置
and then posing with Rotates, moving to another position,
然后旋转它 移动到另一个位置
and posing a Rotate again, and so on.
然后又一次旋转它 诸如此类
So they should be able to Rotate about the base
因此无论他们将台灯底座移到哪个位置
no matter where they Translate it.
他们都必须能够旋转它
But if our deformers operate in the wrong order,
但如果你的变形器按错误的顺序执行
Translate then Rotate, we will run into a problem.
移动然后旋转 我们就会得到一个错误的结果
The rotation of the lamp will move away
旋转台灯
from the pose like this.
会让台灯以这样的姿势移开
That's because we moved the lamp away
这是因为
from the axis of rotation,
我们将台灯从旋转的轴心移开了
which is the initial position of the base.
这个轴心在台灯的初始位置
We solve this problem by having our deformers operate
我们通过采用相反的变形器执行顺序
in the opposite order.
来解决这个问题
First we Rotate about the origin of the base,
首先我们在底座的原始位置旋转
and then we move the base.
然后再移动底座
This dependence on ordering is called non-commutativity.
这种对执行顺序的依赖 叫做非可换性（non-commutativity）
(drum beat)
(鼓声)
Well, you can learn more about this
好吧 你可以从布景与舞台课程中
in the set and staging lesson.
学到更多相关内容
(laughs)
(笑)
(xylophone notes)
(木琴声)
In this next exercise our goal
在下个练习中
is to move our lamp into place
我们的目标是将台灯放到恰当的地方
and then pose him with rotations.
而后旋转它
So you'll need to pay attention to the ordering
因此你需要注意
of your translation and rotational deformers.
移动和旋转变形的顺序
Have fun!
玩得开心!
(laughs) aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(笑) aimozhen.com/pixarinabox